Office of the Vice-President, Legal Affairs fonds
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department
Office of the Vice-President, Legal Affairs fonds
1969 - 2007
F-228
38 cm of textual records
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department Maggie Benston Student Services Building, Rm. 0400 8888 University Dr. Burnaby British Columbia Canada V5A 1S6 Telephone: 778.782.3805 Email: archives@sfu.ca http://www.sfu.ca/archives
Office of the Vice-President, Legal Affairs
The Vice-President, Legal Affairs is the senior University official responsible for coordinating the legal matters of the University. This officer is also in charge of policy development and interpretation, education and training relating to policies and procedures, and managing the University's employment equity program.
The office was previously known as the Office of the Associate Vice-President, Policy, Equity, and Legal (2001-2004) and the Office of the Associate Vice-President, Legal Affairs (2004-2006).
published
Full
Published
Title is based on the name of of the fonds creator.
The fonds consists of superceded policies and procedures.
The arrangement of the material is based on the original file classification system of the creator.
Osborne, Judith; Law and justice
The records were transferred to Archives through the regular application of university Records Retention Schedules and Disposal Authorities (RRSDAs).
As of July 2007, all material has been processed. Further accruals are expected.
For other material relating to superceded and obsolete policies, see the finding aid to F-33, Board of Governors.
Some files may contain personal or confidential information. Access to these files may be restricted as required by law. Files marked "pending review" must be reviewed by an archivist prior to release and, as a result of the review, access restrictions may apply. Please see the file lists and consult the archivist for more details.
File lists are available.
- University policies and procedures, 1969 - 2007; F-228-1; 38 cm of textual records
  published
  - Academic policies (A), 1992 - 2006; F-228-1-1; 6 cm of textual records
    - A 10.06 Appointment of specially funded university chairs, university professors and research fellows, 2000; F-228-1-1-0-1 (Archival box - standard 228-1)
      Textual records
      Pending review
    - A 12.01 Teaching appointments, 2000; F-228-1-1-0-2 (Archival box - standard 228-1)
    - A 12.03 Librarians, 2000; F-228-1-1-0-3 (Archival box - standard 228-1)
    - A 12.08 Adjunct professors, 1992; F-228-1-1-0-4 (Archival box - standard 228-1)
    - A 13.04 Terms of appointment for departmental chairs/directors of schools and other academic administrators, 2000; F-228-1-1-0-5 (Archival box - standard 228-1)
    - A 20.02 Academic salary scales, 2000 - 2004; F-228-1-1-0-6 (Archival box - standard 228-1)
    - A 21.01 (revision A) Benefits(1) for SFUFA bargaining unit members, retirees and visiting faculty, 2005; F-228-1-1-0-7 (Archival box - standard 228-1)
    - A 21.02 Relocation expenses for tenure track faculty, 1992; F-228-1-1-0-8 (Archival box - standard 228-1)
    - A 21.03 Mortgage assistance program, 2001; F-228-1-1-0-9 (Archival box - standard 228-1)
    - A 21.04 Reimbursement of professional development expenses for members of the SFUFA bargaining unit, 2005; F-228-1-1-0-10 (Archival box - standard 228-1)
    - A 21.07 Mortgage interest subsidy, 2005; F-228-1-1-0-11 (Archival box - standard 228-1)
    - A 31.02 Study leave, 2001; F-228-1-1-0-12 (Archival box - standard 228-1)
    - A 31.05 Parental benefits policy, 2000; F-228-1-1-0-13 (Archival box - standard 228-1)
    - A 31.06 Study leave for lecturers, senior lecturers, laboratory instructors, librarians and archivists, 2002; F-228-1-1-0-14 (Archival box - standard 228-1)
    - A 32.01 (revision A) Award for excellence in teaching, 2006; F-228-1-1-0-15 (Archival box - standard 228-1)
  - Administrative polices (AD), 1969 - 2007; F-228-1-2; 18 cm of textual records
    - AD 01.06 (revision A) commercial outlets, advertising and selling on campus, 1980; F-228-1-2-0-1 (Archival box - standard 228-1)
    - AD 01.07 (revision B) Use of university facilities by university community, 1980; F-228-1-2-0-2 (Archival box - standard 228-1)
    - AD 01.08 (revision B) Use of university facilities by off-campus organizations, 1980; F-228-1-2-0-3 (Archival box - standard 228-1)
    - AD 01.10 (revision A) Lost property, 1980; F-228-1-2-0-4 (Archival box - standard 228-1)
    - AD 03.02 (revision G) Travel and business expenses, 2004; F-228-1-2-0-5 (Archival box - standard 228-1)
    - AD 03.10 Internal audit policy, 1986; F-228-1-2-0-6 (Archival box - standard 228-1)
    - AD 09.01 (revision D) Personnel employment policies, 1990; F-228-1-2-0-7 (Archival box - standard 228-1)
    - AD 09.02 (revision F) Establishment of positions, 1990; F-228-1-2-0-8 (Archival box - standard 228-1)
    - AD 09.03 (revision G) Filling of positions, 1994; F-228-1-2-0-9 (Archival box - standard 228-1)
    - AD 09.04 (revision B) Modification of appointments from full-time to part-time, 2004; F-228-1-2-0-10 (Archival box - standard 228-1)
    - AD 09.06 (revision H) Salary administration, 1994; F-228-1-2-0-11 (Archival box - standard 228-1)
    - AD 09.07 (revision I) Group benefit plans, 1994; F-228-1-2-0-12 (Archival box - standard 228-1)
    - AD 09.08 (revision L) Leaves (with and without pay), 2006; F-228-1-2-0-13 (Archival box - standard 228-1)
    - AD 09.09 (revision D) Professional development, 2004; F-228-1-2-0-14 (Archival box - standard 228-1)
    - AD 09.10 (revision A) Tuition waiver, 1990; F-228-1-2-0-15 (Archival box - standard 228-2)
    - AD 09.11 (revision F) Study leave, 1993; F-228-1-2-0-16 (Archival box - standard 228-2)
    - AD 09.13 Working conditions, 1994; F-228-1-2-0-17 (Archival box - standard 228-2)
    - AD 09.17 Problem solving, 1990; F-228-1-2-0-18 (Archival box - standard 228-2)
    - AD 09.18 (revision G) Occupational continuity, 1994; F-228-1-2-0-19 (Archival box - standard 228-2)
    - AD 09.19 Discipline and termination, 1990; F-228-1-2-0-20 (Archival box - standard 228-2)
    - AD 09.21 (revision D) Retirement, 1990; F-228-1-2-0-21 (Archival box - standard 228-2)
    - AD 09.22 (revision F) Reimbursement of professional development expenses, 2005; F-228-1-2-0-22 (Archival box - standard 228-2)
    - AD 10.01 (revision B) Employment policies, 2007; F-228-1-2-0-23 (Archival box - standard 228-2)
    - AD 10.03 Posting and filling of positions, 1999; F-228-1-2-0-24 (Archival box - standard 228-2)
    - AD 10.04 (revision A) Modification of appointments from full-time to part-time, 2004; F-228-1-2-0-25 (Archival box - standard 228-2)
    - AD 10.06 (revision A) Position evaluation and salary administration, 2000; F-228-1-2-0-26 (Archival box - standard 228-2)
    - AD 10.08 (revision D) Leaves with and without pay, 2007; F-228-1-2-0-27 (Archival box - standard 228-2)
    - AD 10.09 Professional development leave, 1999; F-228-1-2-0-28 (Archival box - standard 228-2)
    - AD 10.10 (revision B) Professional development, 2004; F-228-1-2-0-29 (Archival box - standard 228-2)
    - AD 10.11 (revision E) Reimbursement of professional development expenses, 2005; F-228-1-2-0-30 (Archival box - standard 228-2)
    - AD 10.13 Work schedules, 1999; F-228-1-2-0-31 (Archival box - standard 228-2)
    - AD 10.17 Problem resolution, 1999; F-228-1-2-0-32 (Archival box - standard 228-2)
    - AD 10.19 Discipline and termination of employment, 1999; F-228-1-2-0-33 (Archival box - standard 228-2)
    - AD 11.01 (revision C) Purchasing policy and responsibility, 1980; F-228-1-2-0-34 (Archival box - standard 228-2)
    - AD 11.02 (revision B) Request for quotation, 1980; F-228-1-2-0-35 (Archival box - standard 228-2)
    - AD 11.03 (revision C) Requisitioning materials and services, 1980; F-228-1-2-0-36 (Archival box - standard 228-2)
    - AD 11.05 (revision A) Emergency purchases, 1980; F-228-1-2-0-37 (Archival box - standard 228-2)
    - AD 11.07 (revision B) Standing and blanket purchase orders, 1980; F-228-1-2-0-38 (Archival box - standard 228-2)
    - AD 11.08 (revision B) Purchase of special equipment, 1980; F-228-1-2-0-39 (Archival box - standard 228-2)
    - AD 11.09 (revision A) Customs clearances, 1969; F-228-1-2-0-40 (Archival box - standard 228-2)
    - AD 11.12 (revision A) Ordering of printing, 1980; F-228-1-2-0-41 (Archival box - standard 228-2)
    - AD 11.14 (revision A) Local purchase orders, 1980; F-228-1-2-0-42 (Archival box - standard 228-2)
    - AD 11.15 Tenders and contracts, 1970; F-228-1-2-0-43 (Archival box - standard 228-2)
    - AD 11.16 (revision A) Damaged shipments, 1980; F-228-1-2-0-44 (Archival box - standard 228-2)
    - AD 11.19 (revision D) Cutoff dates: fiscal year end purchases, 1993; F-228-1-2-0-45 (Archival box - standard 228-2)
    - AD 11.20 Central stores pick-up and delivery services, 1989; F-228-1-2-0-46 (Archival box - standard 228-2)
  - Board of governors policies (B), 1996 - 2004; F-228-1-3; 1 cm of textual records
    - B 10.01 (revision B) Rules of the board of governors, 2004; F-228-1-3-0-1 (Archival box - standard 228-3)
    - B 10.02 Board committees, 1996; F-228-1-3-0-2 (Archival box - standard 228-3)
  - General policies (GP), 1984 - 2006; F-228-1-4; 6 cm of textual records
    - GP 04 (revision C) Unscheduled cancellations of classes and/or closure of the university -- Burnaby campus, 1995; F-228-1-4-0-1 (Archival box - standard 228-3)
    - GP 09 (revision B) Relocation expenses, 1984; F-228-1-4-0-2 (Archival box - standard 228-3)
    - GP 13 (revision A) The office computer workstation, 1987; F-228-1-4-0-3 (Archival box - standard 228-3)
    - GP 17 (revision A) University occupational health and safety, 1999; F-228-1-4-0-4 (Archival box - standard 228-3)
    - GP 19 (revision B) Employment equity, 1992; F-228-1-4-0-5 (Archival box - standard 228-3)
    - GP 20 (revision A) Endowment management policy, 1998; F-228-1-4-0-6 (Archival box - standard 228-3)
    - GP 23 (revision B) International activities, 2001; F-228-1-4-0-7 (Archival box - standard 228-3)
    - GP 29 (revision B) Search committees for vice-presidents, 2006; F-228-1-4-0-8 (Archival box - standard 228-3)
    - GP 33 Animal/pet policy, 2003; F-228-1-4-0-9 (Archival box - standard 228-3)
  - Information policies (I), F-228-1-5
  - Research policies (R), 1996 - 2003; F-228-1-6; 5 cm of textual records
    - R 20.01 (revision A) University research ethics review, F-228-1-6-0-1 (Archival box - standard 228-3)
    - R 20.02 Biosafety committee, 1999; F-228-1-6-0-2 (Archival box - standard 228-3)
    - R 20.03 Treatment of animals in research and teaching, 2000; F-228-1-6-0-3 (Archival box - standard 228-3)
    - R 20.04 Radiological safety, 1997; F-228-1-6-0-4 (Archival box - standard 228-3)
    - R 20.05 Non-ionizing radiation safety, 2003; F-228-1-6-0-5 (Archival box - standard 228-3)
    - R 40.01 Centres and institutes, 2002; F-228-1-6-0-6 (Archival box - standard 228-3)
    - R 50.02 Personnel funded from research grants -- appendices a, b ,c and d: sample employment letters, 1996; F-228-1-6-0-7 (Archival box - standard 228-3)
  - Teaching policies (T), 1992; F-228-1-7; 1 cm of textual records
    - T 20.01 Grading practices and grade appeals, 1992; F-228-1-7-0-1 (Archival box - standard 228-3)